Mr.  Mutchin, congratulations to you.
[applause]
We have one more productive this evening,
Mr.  Lee W.
[applause]
And Mr.  Wayn has two people tonight.
Dr.  M staff mayor Frank Jackson send a
message tonight and former [clears throat]
city councilman Matt Zone
[laughter]
[applause]
ok everyone this is the final stretch
good evening
so I am here tonight on behalf of former
mayor Frank Jackson is inducting le
and I just want to start by saying it is
truly an honor to stand before you
tonight as a member of the Cleveland
International Hall of Fame on behalf of
Mayor Jackson I am a 2020 inductive we
remember that year and Mayor Frank
Jackson is a proud member of the class
of 2025
tonight we gather to recognize not just
achievement
but life defined by service, resilient
and an unwavering commitment to
community.
Before I go further, I do want to give a
shout out for Lucy Torz um for her
devotion.  It's fitting that they're
both being induced together.
Lee exemplifies
what it means to be a true public
servant.
I have often said that public service is
not for everyone
and it isn't.
It requires sacrifice, humility
and a deep sense of responsibility.
But when it is done right, it becomes
one of the most powerful ways to change
lives and strengthen communities.
Lee embodies that.  He understands that.
His journey began far from Cleveland and
Vietnam where he experienced the
realities of war and displacement.  Yet
from those challenges he felt the life
rooted in service and purpose.  For more
than three decades with the city of
Cleveland, Lee became a trusted present,
a connector,
a mediator, and a bridge between
cultures, neighborhoods, and
institutions.
He helped families reveal their lives.
supported communities in times of need
and brought people together in ways that
leave a lasting impact.
His work extends beyond any single role
or title.  Rather helping um resettle
refugee families, strengthening culture
understanding, or serving as a steady
voice and figure within city hall.  his
influence could be felt across
generations
and importantly his service spend
administration
including his time during the Frank
Jackson administration alongside other
mayors reflects not only his
professionalism but his unwavering
commitment to the people of this city
the city of Cleveland.
So for that we [clears throat] are all
better and Cleveland is stronger because
of your service.
Thank you, Lee.  This is what service
looks like and this is what legacy feels
like.  We thank you.  [clears throat] And and
that was from Mayor Frank Jackson.  On a
personal note, Lee was one of the first
people that I met when I entered CL City
Hall in 1999. I know I was three.  And I
will tell you that what he has done and
how he has served and how he sacrificed
his time, his energy and his talent to
make the city the way it is today and
the strength of the international
community what it is today.  Lee, I
appreciate you.  Now, he's been inspired
by two people today.  So, it's my
privilege and honor to introduce Matt
Zone.  You all know him.  President uh
Griffin uh spoke of him today.  But Matt
wants to personally come up and say some
words about Lee as well.
[applause]
Thank you, Valerie.  And I will be super
brief.  I realize this has been a long
program.  Um, I had the high honor and
privilege of serving as a counselman for
19 years, but I met Lead well before I
was elected to office.  I was a young
boy.  Uh I was 10 years old and my mother
Mary Zone was a council woman.  And in
1975 after the fall of many Vietnamese
immigrants were coming to the United States.
Many of them started to settle on the
near west side where my mother
represented.  And Lee was always somebody
who my mother could call on particularly
as people were trying to assimilate.
When um I became the councelman, Lee was
singularly focused on creating the
Vietnamese community center of creator
Cleveland and he did that right there in
the Gordon Square Arcade at West 65th in
Detroit.  And flash for 22 years later I
was the councilman.  So I got to work
closely with him.  He is a humble
hardwing person.  Um really thrilled that
his son Jason came in from out of town
to be here with him because uh Lee
raised a remarkable young man who's
doing great things as well.  All of you
join and give a warm welcome to our
friend and Hall of Fame and duct D Lee
W.
[applause]
Hold on.  He had to put his classes on.
He's an old man.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen and
all my
My name is L I am very very happy to be
here to receive and a world of Cleveland
International
H off
and I would like to thank you to Mr.  Dan
and Mr.   There is more
information for this evening.
I would like to take this opportunity
to thank you very much to May your policy
Mayor Michael R.
May James Campally
May Fran Jackon and outstanding leader
and customment
and my former director are Mr.
Mr. Williams
[Applause]
Mr.
CU he got the law
he is outstanding leader
and Mr.  L Griffen
director of community relations board
I know after I step down and he moved on
to
that high level become Cy Resident City
of Land and I know next few more years he
will be
a city of living in the future
[applause]
R
and Mr.  Mr. Wa R, Director of Foundation
Margaret W
and outstanding
Mr.
and Mr.  Johnny H
Mr.  Mar
National C Bank
and Mr.
Mit rewardt
mrel
the US
Vietnam veteran
please stand up so the people can recogn
[applause]
He had [singing] me a lot during I worked
for the city of Land
in Vietnamese community.
B
an ch
[applause]
my
I
one thank
Vietnam veteran and I know may fon
Vietnam veteran
both of them
went to Vietnam and for Vietnam World
and I
just
want to sing a short song to thank you
them and All the Vietnam veteran went to
Vietnam
for the freedom of Vietnam.
the
[singing]
in Vietnam
the
up
Rainb
[applause]
at this time I would like to thank you
my family
many of them come here to support me for
my
he
reporter at
many years ago
and now he today
from the Houston Texas
here to support me
Please give the big hand.  [Applause]
Thank you.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
I was born in River
City in Vietnam.
The end of Vietnam World
on April 30, 1975
I took a the first group came to the
USA.
In 1980
I graduated
associate degree at Indiana vocation tax
I
for the community relations
city of
I work
hour to exit new resident from
Vietnamese laun and Cambodian
reset in our city
I also investigate comp and
diversity
awareness workshop
on culture
of in our city.
On May 30,
2012,
I stepped down and took retirement after I worked
for the city of Cleveland for 30 years
and
it was a long long time my friend.
[laughter]
also because
my lovely
bon
had cancer
I need at home to take care of her but
later on away on August 162
I wish her here with me tonight.
In the year of 2000
while I worked for community relations
I never forgot a big project we called
Asian American resource directory.
It is the idea for my
manager Mr.  Jack Wner.
I think that's a very good project.
So we submit to Michael R
it.  Thank you.
I a meeting with the Asian Pacific American
Federation.
Mr.  David and Mr.  Frank Nam Chinese
consolidate
B
association
Mr.
President
and Mr.  Mar
from National City Bank.
All of them and support
that time we have only telephone and
computer but we don't have internet or
Google like today.
book
Asian American Resort Directory
this book and I think we s a lot
tounityad
library to
so in that book we have city ofland
service organization from Chinese to
Capodian and
church and temple of Asian community
agency and
association
business community service healthc legal
media professional religious institution
and restaurant
we finish it in summer
Thank you very much.
[applause]
Ladies and gentlemen,
one of the important days in the Vietnam
history is April 30, 1975.
the end of Vietnam
years ago
the
by theing
to the border of Cambodia
to
and
a new in the United Stat of America
myself
I would like to take this opportunity to
thank you USA and South Vietnam Sia
who fought for freedom at well at the
city of
agency chur and individuals
for the outstanding
of and providing assistant for the
Vietnam refugee recettlement in
Cleveland, Ohio, USA.
We have you to remember
America
5000 airline her
500,000
sa Vietnam
hero
1 million hero Vietnam
people
ultimate sacrifice for our freedom
today.
God and Buddha bless your family.
Thank you very much.  Thank you very
much.  [Applause][Cheers]
Mr.  Win, congratulations.
[applause]
I had the pleasure of working with your
son, Jason.  He's right there back at
Channel 3 back of the day, Jason.  It's
good to see you.  Obviously, your dad
loves you very much.  And as my
grandfather would say, Mr.  Win, you're
done well.  He's a great kid.
Can we please get a round of applause
for all of our inductors?
[yelling]
Also want to say one of the
proceedings is in addition to the ones
I told you earlier the will also get one
from Senator John.  Once again has been
my pleasure to be your MC tonight as we
do every year.  Mr.  Dan Hanson is going
to give some final remarks and give his
famous toast.  D
stay up here R big hand for R
doesn't he
channel
I don't know the basketall games where
you are I don't know where any of the
games are anymore you know it's but this
is what we do the important thing is all
the inducements immediately when we adjourn
now come to the front for your class
photo.  class photo is very important.
It's in the book every year.  It's going to
be in the West Reserve Historical
Society.  It's everywhere.  So come up
right away.  You can pose later.  So the
last thing we do and you can start
nominating for next year, we raise our
glasses and we toast a new class.  So we
raise your glass, we toast Andy and
the other Andy and Katherine and Lee and
Lucy say whatever your language will do
it.  I'm going to say SL for my Irish
friends.  But here's a toast to them.
Cheers.
Thank you all for coming.
Class, come up for your picture and then
take pictures and thanks for coming.  We'll
see you next year.